♪If I am gone from this world,
will the dark night collapse?♪
♪If I never return
to guard by your side♪
♪If I seal away our encounter
and erase all trace♪
♪Like endless snow
falling into the deep sea♪
♪This life is but a fleeting illusion,
yet it gave me courage♪
♪Love is a miracle♪
=Spring Over Phoenix Pond=
(Adapted from Qin An'an's
"Spring Over Phoenix Pond")
=Episode 20=
The Marquis Yongping
requests an audience.
I pay my respects to Your Majesty.
Why is it you?
Where is Liu?
Your Majesty,
Consort Great Liu is...
Father,
I'm afraid you will not
get to see Consort Great Liu.
She was killed.
It was Qi Zhen who did it.
Prince Qi.
I'm innocent!
How could this happen?
My poor sister.
His Majesty and I
didn't even get to see you one last time.
How could you leave us just like that?
Your Majesty.
You must stand up for my sister.
Qi Zhao.
You speak.
Your Majesty,
I saw my father poison Consort Great Liu
with my own eyes.
Qi Zhao!
You rebellious son!
You're conspiring with outsiders
to frame me!
Tell Qi Zhao to come here and tell him
that Qi Yuan killed Qi Jin.
Consort Great Liu is about to return.
Please look after the Qi family
for me.
Qi Yuan and the others
have found
Consort Great Liu's whereabouts.
They will bring her home
in the next few days.
His Lordship sent me to bring food.
Rebellious son!
How dare you!
Your Majesty!
I am innocent!
Tell me.
What exactly is going on?
Your Majesty,
I saw for myself
that the Marquis Yongping
went through a lot
to bring Consort Great Liu back.
If he intended to harm her,
why wait until Her Highness
returned to the capital?
There must be more to this.
Please investigate carefully,
Your Majesty.
The evidence is conclusive.
Consort Great Liu's body
is in Guanyin Temple.
What more do you need to investigate?
Your Majesty...
Father...
All of you, shut up!
Guards,
take Qi Zhen down first.
Your Majesty!
I am innocent!
- Consort Great Liu requests an audience.
- Your Majesty.
It has been many years.
How have you been, Your Majesty?
Liu...
Liu.
Just now...
Just now,
they said...
I was dead.
Your Majesty,
the Marquis Qi went
through so much trouble
to bring me back.
You should not doubt him.
It is some people
with sinister intentions.
Impossible.
You are not her.
I saw it with my own eyes.
My father poisoned Consort Great Liu.
You are not her.
Your Majesty,
if you don't trust me,
may I ask if you still remember
"Snow falling on plum branches,
and never regretting it"?
The moon's shadow is sparse,
and I return with snow in my arms.
We wrote those lines together
for the Qionghua Tune.
Only you and I knew them.
It is not real.
Liu...
It really is you.
Your Majesty, she is fake.
She is not real.
Shut up.
You framed your own father
and deceived the Emperor.
What was your plan?
Your Majesty.
Guards!
Take him away.
Interrogate him thoroughly.
Your Majesty!
Qi Zhao.
How dare you deceive me!
Fortunately, Father saw through it all.
Take him away.
Your Majesty!
- Your Majesty!
- Go.
I'm being framed, Your Majesty!
I'm being framed!
Liu,
it's good that you are back.
All these years,
I have thought of you
every moment of every day.
I never even dared to imagine
that one day,
the two of us would see each other again.
Back then, it was all
because of the bandits
that we were separated.
I have been heartbroken ever since.
Your Majesty,
I have missed you day and night.
Even in my dreams,
I was reunited with Your Majesty.
As for those bandits,
Your Majesty need not blame yourself.
I have come here today
to settle accounts with
the true culprit behind those bandits.
Your Majesty,
the true culprit behind the bandits
was my own sister.
Please, Your Majesty,
for the Commandery Princess
and the Prince Consort
who died in that bandit attack,
please uphold justice.
Liu,
get up first.
Consort Little Liu,
you actually murdered your own sister.
Your Majesty,
I...
I am innocent!
Father,
my mother has a pure and kind nature.
She would never murder her own sister.
Your Majesty,
my sister and I grew up together.
How could I possibly have murdered her?
Sister,
we've finally reunited
after so many years.
Why would you
slander me?
Could it be
I'm the only one
who still remembers those days?
All these years,
I have always dreamed of you.
When we were children,
you climbed a tree
to help me get my kite.
Then you accidentally fell down
and had a scar on your hand.
So many years have passed.
Has that scar faded?
Sister.
Where is your scar?
Father,
she is not Consort Great Liu.
Qi Yuan!
Your Majesty,
how can it be Qi Yuan?
How dare you!
You disguised yourself
as Consort Great Liu and fooled me.
And you tried to frame
Consort Little Liu too.
Your Majesty,
Consort Great Liu's sudden death
wasn't done by the Qi family.
But the bandit incident
was indeed done by Consort Little Liu.
Please investigate carefully,
Your Majesty.
Nonsense!
Your Majesty,
Consort Great Liu's sudden death
must have some hidden truth.
Please allow me to
investigate it thoroughly.
The Qi family
has long been in league
with Xiao Yunting.
Are you trying to destroy the evidence
and deceive His Majesty?
I have no such intention.
I only want to uncover the truth.
Why are you so determined to stop me?
Silence!
Guards.
Take the entire
Marquis Yongping Residence
to the Court of Judicial Review.
Hold them until further notice.
Grandfather!
Yunting.
As a son,
with Father gravely ill,
you've left him aside.
All you do is shield the Qi family.
Guards,
send Prince Jing back
to the Eastern Palace.
Without my decree,
he is not to step out
of the Eastern Palace.
Please think again, Your Majesty.
I have made up my mind.
Do you really want me to
charge you and the Qi family
with forming cliques for private gain?
I obey the decree.
Grandmother.
I didn't think it through.
This is not your fault.
It is the elders' fault.
Look at you two.
You raised such a fine son.
What a lovely family.
Qi Yuan.
At this point,
as long as you agree to marry me,
I can release your whole family.
Prince Qi,
marriage
must be by mutual consent.
Is that so?
You're mad!
If you keep talking nonsense,
I will have their heads cut off.
Let me ask you one more time.
Will you marry me or not?
(Now that I have my grandparents
who love me,)
(and this family,)
(how could I watch them die
because of me?)
Oh, Qi Yuan.
Family really is your weakness.
As long as the Qi family
is in my hands,
you'll do as I say.
This wine
is laced with Paralyzing Powder.
Drink it,
and your martial arts will be crippled.
You'll belong to me forever.
Drink it.
What?
Would you rather watch your grandfather
die right in front of you?
At last, you're mine.
♪How I wish to hold onto
this fleeting warmth♪
♪How I wish to live this life
only for you♪
♪When memories sink
and the heart settles♪
♪Forgetting life, death,
parting, and reunion♪
♪How I wish to stay
only in the moment with you♪
♪Anchoring myself by your side♪